VINCENT ZIMMER

myincentzimmer.netlify.app

(763) 301-2865

in linkedin.com/in/vincent-zimmer-29776a202

<u>vlz12@yahoo.com</u>

SUMMARY

Highly motivated recent graduate from Saint Cloud State University with a Bachelors of Science in Software Engineering and nearly 2 years of professional experience as a Full-Stack Software Engineer. Strong commitment to learning new technologies, collaborating with teammates, and developing applications with the end-user in mind. Thrives in fast-paced environments and always strives to make a difference.

EXPERIENCE

Intern to Part-Time Full Stack Software Engineer, Ecumen — Remote

June 2021-March 2023

- Contributed to the development of a SaaS platform for long-term healthcare facilities that enabled users to track patient antibiotics and infections, ensuring accurate record keeping and medication management.
- Designed and implemented new UI and backend features, including facility visitor contact tracing, with a focus on usability and accessibility.
- Utilized SDLC agile methodology with monthly releases, including bug fixes, UI enhancements, and new features.
- Developed a map builder tool that simplified and reduced the time needed to program facility maps for visually
 tracking infections; replaced manual placement of HTML div elements with direct drawing of rooms on the map
 using the mouse, reducing map programming time from hours to just a few minutes; integrated with a database
 to update room names for easy infection tracking in each facility.

Starbucks Barista to Shift Lead, Target — St. Cloud, MN

August 2018-September 2022

- Led a team of baristas to maintain store efficiency, including managing inventory, stocking shelves, and preparing food items.
- Adhered to Target and Starbucks cleanliness standards and policies as well as followed Starbucks routines.
- Demonstrated flexibility and adaptability by working in a fast-paced environment and adjusting to changing customer demands and preferences.
- Maintained the highest standards of product quality, safety, and cleanliness, ensuring that the store was always in compliance with local and federal regulations.
- Utilized advanced communication and problem-solving skills to resolve customer complaints and maintain positive relationships with customers.

EDUCATION

Saint Cloud State University, St. Cloud, MN — BS in Software Engineering Undergraduate Capstone

August 2018-July 2022

- Contributed to the development of a desktop and mobile website that counted and classified vehicles on a road and obtained road conditions using a webcam for the Upper Great Plains Transportation Institute at NDSU.
- Active participant in business events, context model, refined stakeholder requirements, conducted demos, and contributed to software documentation.
- Created UI to support user management plus labeled and classified images for a machine learning model.

Undergraduate Applied Research

• Part of an agile team that developed a mobile app that allowed users to request lawn and snow services from a local provider, similar to Uber.

PSEO at Anoka Ramsey Community College, Coon Rapids, MN

August 2017-May 2018

SKILLS/TOOLS: AJAX, Android, Android Studio, API, Cypress, Eclipse, Figma, GitHub, Google Suite, IntelliJ IDE, iOS, Jira, JSON, Linux, MacOS, MaterialUI, Microsoft Office, npm, Responsive Design, Tensorflow (machine learning), UI Design, UML, VSCode, Webpack, Windows, Wordpress, and Xcode

LANGUAGES: React (2 years), JavaScript/ES5+ (3 years), Next.js (<1 year), HTML (3 years), CSS (3 years), SQL (3 years), Node.js (1 year), Java (5 years), Dart/Flutter (1 year), PHP (2 years), C++ (2 years), JQuery (2 years), Python (2 years), and XML (2 years)